<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>All Publications | NWEA</title>
	<atom:link href="/research/theme/student-growth-accountability-policies/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/research/theme/student-growth-accountability-policies/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 17:53:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Effects of 4-day school weeks on older adolescents: Examining impacts of the schedule on academic achievement, attendance, and behavior in high school</title>
		<link>/research/publication/effects-of-4-day-school-weeks-on-older-adolescents-examining-impacts-of-the-schedule-on-academic-achievement-attendance-and-behavior-in-high-school/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 21:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/publication/effects-of-4-day-school-weeks-on-older-adolescents-examining-impacts-of-the-schedule-on-academic-achievement-attendance-and-behavior-in-high-school/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/effects-of-4-day-school-weeks-on-older-adolescents-examining-impacts-of-the-schedule-on-academic-achievement-attendance-and-behavior-in-high-school/">Effects of 4-day school weeks on older adolescents: Examining impacts of the schedule on academic achievement, attendance, and behavior in high school</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/effects-of-4-day-school-weeks-on-older-adolescents-examining-impacts-of-the-schedule-on-academic-achievement-attendance-and-behavior-in-high-school/">Effects of 4-day school weeks on older adolescents: Examining impacts of the schedule on academic achievement, attendance, and behavior in high school</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scott J. Peters, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/scott-j-peters-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 18:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/scott-j-peters-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Scott J. Peters specializes in educational assessment and data use, gifted and talented student identification, equity within advanced educational opportunities, and effectiveness of educational policy. His research focuses on how</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/scott-j-peters-phd/">Scott J. Peters, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scott J. Peters specializes in educational assessment and data use, gifted and talented student identification, equity within advanced educational opportunities, and effectiveness of educational policy. His research focuses on how schools can leverage assessment data for maximum school and student benefit. His ongoing projects relate to balancing cost, sensitivity, and equity in gifted and talented student identification, how to proactively screen students for advanced learning opportunities, examining growth trajectories for advanced learners, and how to ensure all students have access to advanced learning opportunities.</p>
<p>Prior to coming to NWEA, for 13 years, Dr. Peters served as a professor of assessment and research methodology at the University of Wisconsin &#8211; Whitewater.&nbsp; <span style="font-weight: 400;">His scholarly work has appeared in the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Australian Educational Researcher,&nbsp; AERA Open, Teaching for High Potential, the British Journal of Educational Psychology, Exceptional Children, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">and</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Gifted Child Quarterly</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and many other publications. </span>He received his PhD from Purdue University in educational psychology and applied research methodology.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/scott-j-peters-phd/">Scott J. Peters, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ayesha K. Hashim, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/ayesha-k-hashim-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 18:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/ayesha-k-hashim-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ayesha K. Hashim draws on interdisciplinary and mixed-methods research designs to study the impacts of district-level school policies on student learning, as well as the leadership, organizational, and implementation conditions</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/ayesha-k-hashim-phd/">Ayesha K. Hashim, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ayesha K. Hashim draws on interdisciplinary and mixed-methods research designs to study the impacts of district-level school policies on student learning, as well as the leadership, organizational, and implementation conditions that can explain observed results. Her research covers a range of topics including the integration of technology with standards-based instruction, school choice and accountability, teacher professional development, and COVID recovery. Ayesha’s work has been published in <em>Education Finance and Policy</em>, <em>Economics of Education Review</em>, <em>Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis</em>, <em>Computers and Education</em>, <em>American Journal of Education</em>, and <em>Peabody Journal of Education</em>.</p>
<p>Prior to joining NWEA, Ayesha was an assistant professor at the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill. She completed her PhD in urban education policy, MA in economics, and master’s in public policy at the University of Southern California. She received the New Scholar Award in 2017 from the Association for Education Finance and Policy for her dissertation research.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/ayesha-k-hashim-phd/">Ayesha K. Hashim, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Erin Fahle, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/erin-fahle-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 17:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/erin-fahle-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Erin Fahle investigates how social and school context affects gender, racial/ethnic, and socioeconomic inequalities in student’s access to educational opportunities and subsequent achievement. Dr. Fahle’s goal is to help states,</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/erin-fahle-phd/">Erin Fahle, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Erin Fahle investigates how social and school context affects gender, racial/ethnic, and socioeconomic inequalities in student’s access to educational opportunities and subsequent achievement. Dr. Fahle’s goal is to help states, districts, and schools identify areas for policy and practice interventions that can improve the educational circumstances of children across the U.S. She believes deeply that this work must be done in partnership with school leaders and is committed to designing research that reflects their perspectives. Her work has been published in <em>Educational Researcher</em> and the <em>American Educational Research Journal</em> and featured in media outlets including the <em>New York Times</em>, the <em>Wall Street Journal</em>, and NPR.</p>
<p>Dr. Fahle also serves as the co-director of the <a href="https://edopportunity.org/">Educational Opportunity Project</a>. This initiative, led by Stanford University, aims to make high-quality data and research on U.S. educational opportunity widely accessible to policymakers, practitioners, and parents. Prior to joining NWEA, Dr. Fahle was an assistant professor at St. John’s University. She holds a PhD in education policy from Stanford University and an MS in applied mathematics and statistics from Georgetown University.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/erin-fahle-phd/">Erin Fahle, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Andrew McEachin, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/andrew-mceachin-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 15:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/andrew-mceachin-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Andrew McEachin’s work focuses on helping policymakers and educators make informed decisions about the design and implementation of educational policies, so that data and policies may better support student learning</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/andrew-mceachin-phd/">Andrew McEachin, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Andrew McEachin’s work focuses on helping policymakers and educators make informed decisions about the design and implementation of educational policies, so that data and policies may better support student learning and more equitable opportunities and outcomes for all students. His research seeks to better understand both the determinants of persistent educational inequities and inequalities, and to evaluate policies and programs aimed at mitigating them. His recent work explores policies related to school choice initiatives, student discipline policies, and curricular intensification. As the director of the Collaborative for Student Growth, Dr. McEachin leads an interdisciplinary team of NWEA researchers, and oversees numerous partnerships with researchers from universities, think tanks, grant-funding agencies, and other organizations.</p>
<p>He serves as co-editor of <em>Educational Researcher</em>, on the Board of Directors for the Association for Education Finance and Policy, and teaches courses on statistics and the economics of education at the USC Price School of Public Policy. Prior to joining NWEA, Dr. McEachin was a senior policy researcher at the RAND Corporation, taught educational policy analysis and program evaluation at the Pardee RAND Graduate School and at North Carolina State University, and was an IES Postdoctoral Fellow at University of Virginia&#8217;s Curry School of Education. He holds a PhD in Education Policy and MA in Economics from the University of Southern California.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/andrew-mceachin-phd/">Andrew McEachin, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Looking back: how prior-year attendance impacts starting achievement</title>
		<link>/research/publication/looking-back-how-prior-year-attendance-impacts-starting-achievement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 20:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/publication/looking-back-how-prior-year-attendance-impacts-starting-achievement/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/looking-back-how-prior-year-attendance-impacts-starting-achievement/">Looking back: how prior-year attendance impacts starting achievement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/looking-back-how-prior-year-attendance-impacts-starting-achievement/">Looking back: how prior-year attendance impacts starting achievement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Impacts of school entry age on academic growth through second grade</title>
		<link>/research/publication/impacts-of-school-entry-age-on-academic-growth-through-second-grade/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 18:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/publication/impacts-of-school-entry-age-on-academic-growth-through-second-grade/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/impacts-of-school-entry-age-on-academic-growth-through-second-grade/">Impacts of school entry age on academic growth through second grade</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/impacts-of-school-entry-age-on-academic-growth-through-second-grade/">Impacts of school entry age on academic growth through second grade</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Catching up or falling behind: Measuring middle school achievement trajectories for college readiness</title>
		<link>/research/publication/catching-up-or-falling-behind-measuring-middle-school-achievement-trajectories-for-college-readiness/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 23:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/publication/catching-up-or-falling-behind-measuring-middle-school-achievement-trajectories-for-college-readiness/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/catching-up-or-falling-behind-measuring-middle-school-achievement-trajectories-for-college-readiness/">Catching up or falling behind: Measuring middle school achievement trajectories for college readiness</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/catching-up-or-falling-behind-measuring-middle-school-achievement-trajectories-for-college-readiness/">Catching up or falling behind: Measuring middle school achievement trajectories for college readiness</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Student test engagement and its impact on achievement gap estimates</title>
		<link>/research/publication/student-test-engagement-and-its-impact-on-achievement-gap-estimates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 23:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/publication/student-test-engagement-and-its-impact-on-achievement-gap-estimates/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/student-test-engagement-and-its-impact-on-achievement-gap-estimates/">Student test engagement and its impact on achievement gap estimates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/student-test-engagement-and-its-impact-on-achievement-gap-estimates/">Student test engagement and its impact on achievement gap estimates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to support ELL students: A Q&#038;A with Dr. Jim Soland</title>
		<link>/research/publication/how-to-support-ell-students-a-qa-with-dr-jim-soland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 22:53:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/publication/how-to-support-ell-students-a-qa-with-dr-jim-soland/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/how-to-support-ell-students-a-qa-with-dr-jim-soland/">How to support ELL students: A Q&amp;A with Dr. Jim Soland</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/how-to-support-ell-students-a-qa-with-dr-jim-soland/">How to support ELL students: A Q&amp;A with Dr. Jim Soland</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
