<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Case Study Archives - NWEA</title>
	<atom:link href="/news-center/resource/type/case-study/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/news-center/resource/type/case-study/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:19:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Smart data use helps to close achievement gaps for a Florida district</title>
		<link>/resources/smart-data-use-helps-to-close-achievement-gaps-for-a-florida-district/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffani LeClair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resources/smart-data-use-helps-to-close-achievement-gaps-for-a-florida-district/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After changing their assessment solution to MAP Growth, administrators at Bay District Schools in Florida helped struggling students experience phenomenal growth. Educators could pinpoint instruction and target intervention materials with</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/smart-data-use-helps-to-close-achievement-gaps-for-a-florida-district/">Smart data use helps to close achievement gaps for a Florida district</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After changing their assessment solution to MAP Growth, administrators at Bay District Schools in Florida helped struggling students experience phenomenal growth. Educators could pinpoint instruction and target intervention materials with their test data, and Bay students at the lower end of the achievement spectrum grew beyond what’s considered normal.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/smart-data-use-helps-to-close-achievement-gaps-for-a-florida-district/">Smart data use helps to close achievement gaps for a Florida district</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Strong connection between MAP Growth and state test keeps Indiana district on track</title>
		<link>/resources/strong-connection-between-map-growth-and-state-test-keeps-indiana-district-on-track/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffani LeClair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:13:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resources/strong-connection-between-map-growth-and-state-test-keeps-indiana-district-on-track/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When Rensselaer Central Schools switched to MAP Growth, they wanted to make sure the assessment was strongly aligned to their rigorous Indiana state standards. In fact, they created their own</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/strong-connection-between-map-growth-and-state-test-keeps-indiana-district-on-track/">Strong connection between MAP Growth and state test keeps Indiana district on track</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Rensselaer Central Schools switched to MAP Growth, they wanted to make sure the assessment was strongly aligned to their rigorous Indiana state standards. In fact, they created their own version of a linking study to independently validate the correlation to MAP Growth – and were “very happy” with the outcome.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/strong-connection-between-map-growth-and-state-test-keeps-indiana-district-on-track/">Strong connection between MAP Growth and state test keeps Indiana district on track</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data-Driven Instruction Earns a Rural District National Acclaim</title>
		<link>/resources/data-driven-instruction-earns-a-rural-district-national-acclaim-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffani LeClair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 17:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resources/data-driven-instruction-earns-a-rural-district-national-acclaim-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Learn how one district uses MAP Growth to be recognized as Michigan’s top-performing rural district and earn “A” ratings by the Mackinac Center for Public Policy.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/data-driven-instruction-earns-a-rural-district-national-acclaim-2/">Data-Driven Instruction Earns a Rural District National Acclaim</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Learn how one district uses MAP Growth to be recognized as Michigan’s top-performing rural district and earn “A” ratings by the Mackinac Center for Public Policy.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/data-driven-instruction-earns-a-rural-district-national-acclaim-2/">Data-Driven Instruction Earns a Rural District National Acclaim</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ohio District Uses MAP Growth in High School to Drive Systemic Change</title>
		<link>/resources/ohio-district-uses-map-growth-in-high-school-to-drive-systemic-change/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffani LeClair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 17:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resources/ohio-district-uses-map-growth-in-high-school-to-drive-systemic-change/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The phenomenal student growth in Ohio’s Southwest Local School District is unique – in that it started by using MAP Growth at the high school level. They created a successful</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/ohio-district-uses-map-growth-in-high-school-to-drive-systemic-change/">Ohio District Uses MAP Growth in High School to Drive Systemic Change</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The phenomenal student growth in Ohio’s Southwest Local School District is unique – in that it started by using MAP Growth at the high school level. They created a successful intervention for struggling students based on their mission to provide academic and social growth for all students every day. Read how they took what they learned and applied it to promote amazing growth at all grade levels.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/ohio-district-uses-map-growth-in-high-school-to-drive-systemic-change/">Ohio District Uses MAP Growth in High School to Drive Systemic Change</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Step Up For Students schools partner with NWEA and see accelerated student growth</title>
		<link>/resources/step-students-schools-partner-nwea-see-accelerated-student-growth/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffani LeClair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resources/step-students-schools-partner-nwea-see-accelerated-student-growth/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Two Florida schools worked with Step Up For Students (SUFS), a scholarship program serving low-income and special needs students, to take the MAP Growth assessment and &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/step-students-schools-partner-nwea-see-accelerated-student-growth/">Step Up For Students schools partner with NWEA and see accelerated student growth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two Florida schools worked with Step Up For Students (SUFS), a scholarship program serving low-income and special needs students, to take the MAP Growth assessment and &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/step-students-schools-partner-nwea-see-accelerated-student-growth/">Step Up For Students schools partner with NWEA and see accelerated student growth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kansas School Uses MAP Skills to Close Gaps for All Students</title>
		<link>/resources/kansas-school-uses-map-skills-close-gaps-students/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffani LeClair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 17:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resources/kansas-school-uses-map-skills-close-gaps-students/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>El Dorado Middle School is using MAP Skills from NWEA to ensure every single student is getting instruction where they need it most. And it’s already proving to have a</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/kansas-school-uses-map-skills-close-gaps-students/">Kansas School Uses MAP Skills to Close Gaps for All Students</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>El Dorado Middle School is using MAP Skills from NWEA to ensure every single student is getting instruction where they need it most. And it’s already proving to have a huge impact on student growth and achievement. El Dorado students are showing improvement on their state assessments – and on their MAP Growth tests.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/kansas-school-uses-map-skills-close-gaps-students/">Kansas School Uses MAP Skills to Close Gaps for All Students</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Engaging Teachers and Equipping Them to Lead</title>
		<link>/resources/engaging-teachers-equipping-lead/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffani LeClair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 21:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resources/engaging-teachers-equipping-lead/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At Somerdale Park School District in New Jersey, the leadership wanted to strengthen teachers’ capacity to track student growth and progress. To do this, they knew the district needed to</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/engaging-teachers-equipping-lead/">Engaging Teachers and Equipping Them to Lead</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At Somerdale Park School District in New Jersey, the leadership wanted to strengthen teachers’ capacity to track student growth and progress. To do this, they knew the district needed to enhance its “ability to accurately assess and accurately drive instruction.” But they also knew that new tools and assessments require teacher engagement, a shared vision, and professional learning support. Read how they are engaging NWEA Professional Learning and data coaching to use MAP Growth data to its fullest potential.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/engaging-teachers-equipping-lead/">Engaging Teachers and Equipping Them to Lead</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A High-Performing District Uses Data to Aim Even Higher</title>
		<link>/resources/a-high-performing-district-uses-data-to-aim-even-higher/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffani LeClair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 07:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resources/a-high-performing-district-uses-data-to-aim-even-higher/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In 2011, Panhandle Independent School District in Texas began using MAP® Growth™ and MAP Growth K-2 interim assessments. With over 80% of their students meeting proficiency, educational leaders wanted to</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/a-high-performing-district-uses-data-to-aim-even-higher/">A High-Performing District Uses Data to Aim Even Higher</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 2011, Panhandle Independent School District in Texas began using MAP® Growth<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> and MAP Growth K-2 interim assessments. With over 80% of their students meeting proficiency, educational leaders wanted to use MAP Growth data to illuminate the learning needs of their high-performing students so teachers could focus on enrichment activities. But soon they began to explore the multiple benefits MAP Growth provides. Within two years they had expanded their MAP Growth use to cover four measurement needs.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/a-high-performing-district-uses-data-to-aim-even-higher/">A High-Performing District Uses Data to Aim Even Higher</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How young learners excel at this Ohio charter school</title>
		<link>/resources/how-young-learners-excel-at-this-ohio-charter-school/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffani LeClair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 07:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resources/how-young-learners-excel-at-this-ohio-charter-school/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Stepstone Academy is a Cleveland-based, urban charter school with an innovative blended learning model. Stepstone’s leaders knew they needed a research-based assessment like MAP Growth K-2 to support differentiation and</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/how-young-learners-excel-at-this-ohio-charter-school/">How young learners excel at this Ohio charter school</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stepstone Academy is a Cleveland-based, urban charter school with an innovative blended learning model. Stepstone’s leaders knew they needed a research-based assessment like MAP Growth K-2 to support differentiation and track performance against rigorous state standards. Learn how computer adaptive MAP Growth K-2 fits with their technology-based instruction focused on student growth.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/how-young-learners-excel-at-this-ohio-charter-school/">How young learners excel at this Ohio charter school</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Comprehensive Assessment Planning</title>
		<link>/resources/comprehensive-assessment-planning/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffani LeClair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 07:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resources/comprehensive-assessment-planning/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>North Mason Schools began using MAP assessments in 2007, testing 2nd through 8th graders three times a year to assess their readiness for state exams. But individual schools and classrooms</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/comprehensive-assessment-planning/">Comprehensive Assessment Planning</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="LEFT">North Mason Schools began using MAP assessments in 2007, testing 2nd through 8th graders three times a year to assess their readiness for state exams. But individual schools and classrooms were still conducting a variety of benchmark assessments – without correlating that data with MAP results – and some educators at North Mason felt they were missing out on the full benefits of a coordinated testing plan. When NWEA invited them to participate in a full-day comprehensive assessment planning workshop, they saw it as the first step toward making a needed change.</p>
<p align="LEFT">
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resources/comprehensive-assessment-planning/">Comprehensive Assessment Planning</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
