<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Researchers Archive - NWEA</title>
	<atom:link href="/research/our-researchers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/research/our-researchers/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 17:40:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Kari Hodge, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/kari-hodge-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 18:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/kari-hodge-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Kari Hodge manages the MAP Reading Fluency psychometric solutions team at NWEA. Her research interests include Rasch models, small sample equating, standard setting, and using psychometrics for data-driven decision making.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/kari-hodge-phd/">Kari Hodge, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kari Hodge manages the MAP Reading Fluency psychometric solutions team at NWEA. Her research interests include Rasch models, small sample equating, standard setting, and using psychometrics for data-driven decision making. Dr. Hodge has authored four book chapters and published more than 15 articles in peer-reviewed journals such as the <em>Journal of Applied Measurement</em>, <em>Journal of</em> <em>Applied Testing Technology</em>, and <em>Educational and Psychological Measurement</em>. Prior to joining NWEA, Dr. Hodge was an educator for more than 10 years with experience teaching elementary through doctoral-level courses. She brings to NWEA over 15 years of assessment development and psychometric experience. Dr. Hodge holds a PhD in Educational Psychology from Baylor University. She also holds a bachelor’s degree in education and an M.Ed. in Curriculum and Instruction.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/kari-hodge-phd/">Kari Hodge, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scott J. Peters, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/scott-j-peters-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 18:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/scott-j-peters-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Scott J. Peters specializes in educational assessment and data use, gifted and talented student identification, equity within advanced educational opportunities, and effectiveness of educational policy. His research focuses on how</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/scott-j-peters-phd/">Scott J. Peters, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scott J. Peters specializes in educational assessment and data use, gifted and talented student identification, equity within advanced educational opportunities, and effectiveness of educational policy. His research focuses on how schools can leverage assessment data for maximum school and student benefit. His ongoing projects relate to balancing cost, sensitivity, and equity in gifted and talented student identification, how to proactively screen students for advanced learning opportunities, examining growth trajectories for advanced learners, and how to ensure all students have access to advanced learning opportunities.</p>
<p>Prior to coming to NWEA, for 13 years, Dr. Peters served as a professor of assessment and research methodology at the University of Wisconsin &#8211; Whitewater.&nbsp; <span style="font-weight: 400;">His scholarly work has appeared in the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Australian Educational Researcher,&nbsp; AERA Open, Teaching for High Potential, the British Journal of Educational Psychology, Exceptional Children, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">and</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Gifted Child Quarterly</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and many other publications. </span>He received his PhD from Purdue University in educational psychology and applied research methodology.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/scott-j-peters-phd/">Scott J. Peters, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ayesha K. Hashim, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/ayesha-k-hashim-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 18:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/ayesha-k-hashim-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ayesha K. Hashim draws on interdisciplinary and mixed-methods research designs to study the impacts of district-level school policies on student learning, as well as the leadership, organizational, and implementation conditions</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/ayesha-k-hashim-phd/">Ayesha K. Hashim, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ayesha K. Hashim draws on interdisciplinary and mixed-methods research designs to study the impacts of district-level school policies on student learning, as well as the leadership, organizational, and implementation conditions that can explain observed results. Her research covers a range of topics including the integration of technology with standards-based instruction, school choice and accountability, teacher professional development, and COVID recovery. Ayesha’s work has been published in <em>Education Finance and Policy</em>, <em>Economics of Education Review</em>, <em>Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis</em>, <em>Computers and Education</em>, <em>American Journal of Education</em>, and <em>Peabody Journal of Education</em>.</p>
<p>Prior to joining NWEA, Ayesha was an assistant professor at the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill. She completed her PhD in urban education policy, MA in economics, and master’s in public policy at the University of Southern California. She received the New Scholar Award in 2017 from the Association for Education Finance and Policy for her dissertation research.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/ayesha-k-hashim-phd/">Ayesha K. Hashim, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Erin Fahle, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/erin-fahle-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 17:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/erin-fahle-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Erin Fahle investigates how social and school context affects gender, racial/ethnic, and socioeconomic inequalities in student’s access to educational opportunities and subsequent achievement. Dr. Fahle’s goal is to help states,</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/erin-fahle-phd/">Erin Fahle, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Erin Fahle investigates how social and school context affects gender, racial/ethnic, and socioeconomic inequalities in student’s access to educational opportunities and subsequent achievement. Dr. Fahle’s goal is to help states, districts, and schools identify areas for policy and practice interventions that can improve the educational circumstances of children across the U.S. She believes deeply that this work must be done in partnership with school leaders and is committed to designing research that reflects their perspectives. Her work has been published in <em>Educational Researcher</em> and the <em>American Educational Research Journal</em> and featured in media outlets including the <em>New York Times</em>, the <em>Wall Street Journal</em>, and NPR.</p>
<p>Dr. Fahle also serves as the co-director of the <a href="https://edopportunity.org/">Educational Opportunity Project</a>. This initiative, led by Stanford University, aims to make high-quality data and research on U.S. educational opportunity widely accessible to policymakers, practitioners, and parents. Prior to joining NWEA, Dr. Fahle was an assistant professor at St. John’s University. She holds a PhD in education policy from Stanford University and an MS in applied mathematics and statistics from Georgetown University.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/erin-fahle-phd/">Erin Fahle, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Miles Davison, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/miles-davison-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 23:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/miles-davison-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Miles Davison specializes in using quantitative and mixed-methodologies to examine how K-12 intervention policies and programs impact equity in schools. His research is driven by a desire to assist schools</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/miles-davison-phd/">Miles Davison, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Miles Davison specializes in using quantitative and mixed-methodologies to examine how K-12 intervention policies and programs impact equity in schools. His research is driven by a desire to assist schools in creating optimal learning environments for students. He is particularly interested in understanding how particular processes and mechanisms associated with school policies ultimately impact student behavioral and academic outcomes.&nbsp; Specifically, his recent work has focused on changes in school disciplinary practices and disparities after the implementation of restorative justice policies. Through this work, Miles has gained a passion for producing research that is actionable and relevant to policymakers and practitioners.</p>
<p>Dr. Davison holds a PhD in sociology from the University of California, Irvine.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/miles-davison-phd/">Miles Davison, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Katherine Lazenby, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/katherine-lazenby-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 17:08:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/katherine-lazenby-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Kat’s research interests include authentic, phenomenon-based learning experiences in science classrooms. She is especially interested in developing and using learning progressions to support and assess students’ competence with scientific practices,</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/katherine-lazenby-phd/">Katherine Lazenby, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kat’s research interests include authentic, phenomenon-based learning experiences in science classrooms. She is especially interested in developing and using learning progressions to support and assess students’ competence with scientific practices, such as modeling and explaining scientific phenomena. Kat completed her PhD in chemistry and MA in educational measurement and statistics at the University of Iowa. Prior to joining NWEA, Kat worked in discipline-based education research, primarily in chemistry contexts, at San Diego State University and the University of Iowa.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/katherine-lazenby-phd/">Katherine Lazenby, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Susan Kowalski, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/susan-kowalski-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 17:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/susan-kowalski-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Susan Kowalski began her career in science education teaching high school physics and physical science in Bloomington, MN. She completed her PhD in curriculum and instruction from the University of</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/susan-kowalski-phd/">Susan Kowalski, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Susan Kowalski began her career in science education teaching high school physics and physical science in Bloomington, MN. She completed her PhD in curriculum and instruction from the University of Minnesota and the spent several years developing and researching curricula and professional learning experiences at BSCS Science Learning. Her current work investigates new approaches to three-dimensional assessment in support of the Next Generation Science Standards. She is focused on how teachers might learn to more effectively use assessment data to inform their day-to-day science instruction and enhance equitable learning opportunities for students.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/susan-kowalski-phd/">Susan Kowalski, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Donald Williams</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/donald-williams/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/donald-williams/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Donny Williams is a research scientist with over five years of experience in advanced statistical methodology, including mixed models, causal inference and time series, meta-analysis, and Bayesian statistics. He specializes</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/donald-williams/">Donald Williams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donny Williams is a research scientist with over five years of experience in advanced statistical methodology, including mixed models, causal inference and time series, meta-analysis, and Bayesian statistics. He specializes in developing statistical software for solving problems in the social-behavioral sciences. He is the author of 30 peer-reviewed publications, including high-impact work appearing in prestigious quantitative journals such as <em>Psychological Methods</em> and <em>Multivariate Behavior Research</em>. Donny is a PhD candidate in quantitative psychology at the University of California, Davis.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/donald-williams/">Donald Williams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fang Peng, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/fang-peng/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 15:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/fang-peng/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Fang Peng works with the MAP Reading Fluency assessment. Among her interests and areas of expertise are computerized adaptive testing, measurement validity, early childhood development, and applications of natural language</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/fang-peng/">Fang Peng, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fang Peng works with the MAP Reading Fluency assessment. Among her interests and areas of expertise are computerized adaptive testing, measurement validity, early childhood development, and applications of natural language processing and machine learning in assessment contexts. Prior to joining NWEA in 2022, Fang worked as a psychometrician at the National Council of State Boards of Nursing where she gained extensive operational and research experience in large-scale licensure examinations. Fang holds a PhD in Educational Psychology with a concentration in Measurement, Evaluation, Statistics, and Assessment from the University of Illinois at Chicago.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/fang-peng/">Fang Peng, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Helena Connolly, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/helena-connolly/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 01:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/helena-connolly/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Helena Connolly is a learning scientist whose research focuses on math and science learning, non-routine problem solving, motivation, and teacher adaptivity. Helena primarily conducts experimental and mixed methods research with</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/helena-connolly/">Helena Connolly, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Helena Connolly is a learning scientist whose research focuses on math and science learning, non-routine problem solving, motivation, and teacher adaptivity. Helena primarily conducts experimental and mixed methods research with K-12 students and teachers. As a former elementary school teacher, Helena seeks to understand various pedagogical approaches and how they affect individual learners. Prior to joining NWEA, Helena explored these questions as a research fellow at the Institute for Learning Technologies at Teachers College, Columbia University, where she earned a PhD in cognitive science in education.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/helena-connolly/">Helena Connolly, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
