<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>All Publications | NWEA</title>
	<atom:link href="/research/theme/assessments-in-spanish/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/research/theme/assessments-in-spanish/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 17:48:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Spanish MAP Reading Fluency content guide</title>
		<link>/research/publication/spanish-map-reading-fluency-content-guide/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 23:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/publication/spanish-map-reading-fluency-content-guide/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/spanish-map-reading-fluency-content-guide/">Spanish MAP Reading Fluency content guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/spanish-map-reading-fluency-content-guide/">Spanish MAP Reading Fluency content guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spanish MAP Growth Reading technical report</title>
		<link>/research/publication/spanish-map-growth-reading-technical-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 20:04:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/publication/spanish-map-growth-reading-technical-report/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/spanish-map-growth-reading-technical-report/">Spanish MAP Growth Reading technical report</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/spanish-map-growth-reading-technical-report/">Spanish MAP Growth Reading technical report</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calibration of Spanish MAP Growth Math tests</title>
		<link>/research/publication/calibration-of-spanish-map-growth-math-tests/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 19:52:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/publication/calibration-of-spanish-map-growth-math-tests/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/calibration-of-spanish-map-growth-math-tests/">Calibration of Spanish MAP Growth Math tests</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/calibration-of-spanish-map-growth-math-tests/">Calibration of Spanish MAP Growth Math tests</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shudong Wang, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/shudong-wang-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 03:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/shudong-wang-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Shudong Wang focuses on product design and development, including psychometric development of MAP Reading Fluency and MAP Growth Spanish Reading. His research interests include adaptive testing and generalized linear mixed-model</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/shudong-wang-phd/">Shudong Wang, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shudong Wang focuses on product design and development, including psychometric development of MAP Reading Fluency and MAP Growth Spanish Reading. His research interests include adaptive testing and generalized linear mixed-model applications in educational measurement and psychometric research. Dr. Wang has published over 20 peer-reviewed journal articles and book chapters. He has presented at numerous conferences, including NCME, AERA, and CCSSO, on topics such as CAT item selection and quality of student scoring, effects of CAT designs on content coverage and efficiency, and accuracy of student ability estimations. Prior to joining NWEA in 2009, he was a senior psychometrician at ETS. Dr. Wang holds a PhD in educational research methodology from the University of Pittsburgh.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/shudong-wang-phd/">Shudong Wang, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Patrick Meyer, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/patrick-meyer-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 02:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/patrick-meyer-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Patrick Meyer manages the team of psychometricians, statistical analysts, and project managers involved in the district division of NWEA. This team conducts psychometric research for assessments such as MAP Growth</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/patrick-meyer-phd/">Patrick Meyer, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Patrick Meyer manages the team of psychometricians, statistical analysts, and project managers involved in the district division of NWEA. This team conducts psychometric research for assessments such as MAP Growth and MAP Reading Fluency. His research interests include IRT, psychometric software design, and the psychometric characteristics of teaching measures. Dr. Meyer is the inventor and lead developer of jMetrik, an open-source software program used in over 20 countries. He has authored two books and published over 20 articles in peer-reviewed journals such as the Journal of Educational Measurement, Applied Psychological Measurement, and Educational and Psychological Measurement. He has conducted 25 standard-setting workshops in the licensure and certification field, as well as numerous workshops on psychometric theory and the use of jMetrik for data analysis. Prior to joining NWEA in 2018, Dr. Meyer worked as an associate professor with tenure in the Curry School of Education at the University of Virginia, where he taught courses in educational measurement and applied statistics. He began his academic career in 2004 as an assistant professor at James Madison University’s Center for Assessment and Research Studies. Dr. Meyer holds a PhD in educational psychology and research from the University of South Carolina.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/patrick-meyer-phd/">Patrick Meyer, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Xueming (Sylvia) Li, EdD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/xueming-sylvia-li-edd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 02:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/xueming-sylvia-li-edd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Xueming (Sylvia) Li focuses on psychometric issues related to MAP Growth. Her research interests include computer-based testing, applications of IRT, test validity, cross-cultural assessment, and test score linking and equating.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/xueming-sylvia-li-edd/">Xueming (Sylvia) Li, EdD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Xueming (Sylvia) Li focuses on psychometric issues related to MAP Growth. Her research interests include computer-based testing, applications of IRT, test validity, cross-cultural assessment, and test score linking and equating. Prior to joining NWEA in 2015, she received a doctoral degree in research, educational measurement, and psychometrics from the University of Massachusetts Amherst.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/xueming-sylvia-li-edd/">Xueming (Sylvia) Li, EdD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
