<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>All Publications | NWEA</title>
	<atom:link href="/research/theme/learning-standards-alignment/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/research/theme/learning-standards-alignment/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 17:51:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Who Moved the Mathematics?: The Need for IMPACT</title>
		<link>/research/publication/who-moved-the-mathematics-the-need-for-impact/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 22:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/publication/who-moved-the-mathematics-the-need-for-impact/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/who-moved-the-mathematics-the-need-for-impact/">Who Moved the Mathematics?: The Need for IMPACT</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/who-moved-the-mathematics-the-need-for-impact/">Who Moved the Mathematics?: The Need for IMPACT</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arguing about the effectiveness of assessments for the classroom</title>
		<link>/research/publication/arguing-about-the-effectiveness-of-assessments-for-the-classroom/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 19:43:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/publication/arguing-about-the-effectiveness-of-assessments-for-the-classroom/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/arguing-about-the-effectiveness-of-assessments-for-the-classroom/">Arguing about the effectiveness of assessments for the classroom</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/arguing-about-the-effectiveness-of-assessments-for-the-classroom/">Arguing about the effectiveness of assessments for the classroom</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Effects of computerized adaptive test designs on content coverage and efficiency of reading comprehension test with passages aligned to Common Core State Standards</title>
		<link>/research/publication/effects-of-computerized-adaptive-test-designs-on-content-coverage-and-efficiency-of-reading-comprehension-test-with-passages-aligned-to-common-core-state-standards/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 19:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/publication/effects-of-computerized-adaptive-test-designs-on-content-coverage-and-efficiency-of-reading-comprehension-test-with-passages-aligned-to-common-core-state-standards/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/effects-of-computerized-adaptive-test-designs-on-content-coverage-and-efficiency-of-reading-comprehension-test-with-passages-aligned-to-common-core-state-standards/">Effects of computerized adaptive test designs on content coverage and efficiency of reading comprehension test with passages aligned to Common Core State Standards</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/publication/effects-of-computerized-adaptive-test-designs-on-content-coverage-and-efficiency-of-reading-comprehension-test-with-passages-aligned-to-common-core-state-standards/">Effects of computerized adaptive test designs on content coverage and efficiency of reading comprehension test with passages aligned to Common Core State Standards</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Garron Gianopulos, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/garron-gianopulos-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 03:03:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/garron-gianopulos-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Garron Gianopulos leads NWEA’s through-year assessment design on GMAP. Dr. Gianopulos has a broad interest in the practical application of IRT in the development of formative, interim, and summative assessments,</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/garron-gianopulos-phd/">Garron Gianopulos, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Garron Gianopulos leads NWEA’s through-year assessment design on GMAP. Dr. Gianopulos has a broad interest in the practical application of IRT in the development of formative, interim, and summative assessments, and his latest research interests have focused on the use of explanatory IRT, structural equation modeling, and data visualization techniques to validate theories of learning. Prior to joining NWEA in 2018, he was a psychometrician at North Carolina State University, the North Carolina Department of Public Instruction (NCDPI), Professional Testing Inc., and the University of South Florida. While at NCDPI, Dr. Gianopulos led the development of end-of-year and end-of-course summative assessments in mathematics and interim assessments in multiple subjects. As a psychometrician at North Carolina State, he supported the development of formative diagnostic mathematics assessments centered around learning trajectories. Dr. Gianopulos also served on the North Carolina TAC until his transition to NWEA. Dr. Gianopulos holds a doctorate in curriculum and instruction with an emphasis in educational measurement and evaluation with a cognate in psychometrics from the University of South Florida.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/garron-gianopulos-phd/">Garron Gianopulos, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shudong Wang, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/shudong-wang-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 03:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/shudong-wang-phd/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Shudong Wang focuses on product design and development, including psychometric development of MAP Reading Fluency and MAP Growth Spanish Reading. His research interests include adaptive testing and generalized linear mixed-model</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/shudong-wang-phd/">Shudong Wang, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shudong Wang focuses on product design and development, including psychometric development of MAP Reading Fluency and MAP Growth Spanish Reading. His research interests include adaptive testing and generalized linear mixed-model applications in educational measurement and psychometric research. Dr. Wang has published over 20 peer-reviewed journal articles and book chapters. He has presented at numerous conferences, including NCME, AERA, and CCSSO, on topics such as CAT item selection and quality of student scoring, effects of CAT designs on content coverage and efficiency, and accuracy of student ability estimations. Prior to joining NWEA in 2009, he was a senior psychometrician at ETS. Dr. Wang holds a PhD in educational research methodology from the University of Pittsburgh.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/shudong-wang-phd/">Shudong Wang, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ted Coe, PhD</title>
		<link>/research/our-researchers/ted-coe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Hay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/research/our-researchers/ted-coe/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ted Coe draws on more than 25 years of experience as a teacher, professor, department chair, administrator, and non-profit director to weave together thought-provoking perspectives in mathematics education. He is</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/ted-coe/">Ted Coe, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ted Coe draws on more than 25 years of experience as a teacher, professor, department chair, administrator, and non-profit director to weave together thought-provoking perspectives in mathematics education. He is energetic and passionate about mathematics teaching and learning and has worked full-time as a high school mathematics teacher, a community college faculty member, the mathematics chair at two community colleges, an assistant dean at the university level, and a director of mathematics. As NWEA’s director of content advocacy and design, Ted works to promote high-quality mathematical experiences for all. His work entails advocating for mathematics both within NWEA and around the nation. Ted earned his BAE, MEd, and PhD degrees from Arizona State University, each with a focus on mathematics education.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/research/our-researchers/ted-coe/">Ted Coe, PhD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
