<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>MAP Spanish | Resource Center | NWEA</title>
	<atom:link href="/resource-center/product/map-spanish/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/resource-center/product/map-spanish/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:07:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>MAP Spanish Brochure</title>
		<link>/resource-center/resource/map-spanish-brochure/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 08:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resource-center/resource/map-spanish-brochure/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resource-center/resource/map-spanish-brochure/">MAP Spanish Brochure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resource-center/resource/map-spanish-brochure/">MAP Spanish Brochure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On a mission to help all kids learn</title>
		<link>/resource-center/resource/on-a-mission-to-help-all-kids-learn/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 17:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resource-center/resource/on-a-mission-to-help-all-kids-learn/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Often, an assessment signals the end of something. Perhaps the end of an instructional unit, grade level, or course. NWEA®, a mission-driven, research-based not-for-profit, sees things a bit differently. In</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resource-center/resource/on-a-mission-to-help-all-kids-learn/">On a mission to help all kids learn</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Often, an assessment signals the end of something. Perhaps the end of an instructional unit, grade level, or course. <a href="https://www.nwea.org/">NWEA®</a>, a mission-driven, research-based not-for-profit, sees things a bit differently.</p>
<p>In the 1970s, a small group of educators and researchers from the Pacific Northwest formed NWEA to build and develop a new assessment solution. The goal? Create a precise, reliable way to measure a student’s academic growth—then use the insights as a transformational teaching tool.</p>
<p>Today, more than 40 years on, the Portland, Oregon, based organization remains driven by a commitment to an ambitious mission: Partnering to help all kids learn®. It’s not just a mantra; it’s an obligation present at every level of the company. This isn’t by accident.</p>
<p>“Our mission is who we are,” says CEO Chris Minnich. “You see it in the decisions we make, and in our behaviors.”</p>
<p>That’s why the organization’s not-for-profit status is so important. If there’s ever a question about whether to invest in students and schools, or add money to the bottom line, the decision for NWEA is easy.</p>
<p>“I don’t come to work every day to sell more tests. Because these kids aren’t just numbers,” Minnich says. “If we can help our students grow and improve their academic outcomes, that’s real opportunity. It’s the difference between being able to change their situation, or being stuck in the situation they’re in. And that’s what our mission is. Our mission is every kid, every day.”</p>
<p>Rising to this challenge, NWEA brings the vision of reaching more students into sharper focus in numerous ways.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nwea.org/map-growth/map-spanish/"><strong>MAP® Growth<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> en español</strong></a>: Culturally relevant Spanish-language assessments support Spanish-speaking English learners and students in Spanish immersion programs. MAP Growth and <a href="https://www.nwea.org/map-reading-fluency/">MAP® Reading Fluency<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></a> in Spanish provide equitable assessment tools to help teachers better understand the next steps in learning for more of their students.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nwea.org/accommodations-accessibility/"><strong>Accommodations and accessibility</strong></a>: Assessments are designed from the ground up to remove barriers and improve accommodations for students with disabilities. Features like refreshable braille, screen-reader compatibility, highlighter and eraser, magnification, and keyboard navigation provide students equal opportunities to learn and grow.</li>
<li><strong>Course-specific coverage</strong>: <a href="https://www.nwea.org/blog/2020/help-kids-plan-future-college-explorer/">Secondary students are often left out</a> of conversations around their growth, but assessments for high school–level, course-specific math content, like algebra and geometry, as well as a MAP Growth life sciences assessment, are available for grades 9–12.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nwea.org/blog/2019/how-much-does-science-really-change/"><strong>Science-focused assessment</strong></a>: NWEA offers two interim science assessments: one aligned to state standards, and the other for use with Next Generation Science Standards* for states, schools, and districts that have adopted NGSS. These assessments provide valuable insights for teachers on the science knowledge students possess and support learners as they aspire toward STEM- or STEAM-focused learning.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nwea.org/our-mission/educators-for-equity/"><strong>Educators for Equity Grant Program</strong></a>: To celebrate and empower educators going the extra mile to support student growth, NWEA introduced the Educators for Equity Grant Program in 2019. Each year, the organization awards grants up to $10,000 to educators and not-for-profits that need help funding programs that foster growth for students facing systemic barriers to a high-quality education.</li>
</ul>
<p>Helping all kids learn is a mission without borders, which is why NWEA works with students and teachers in more than 140 countries, supporting learners from pre-K through high school. More than 11 million students take NWEA assessment solutions each year, but wherever there’s a struggling student, the work continues.</p>
<p>As controversy and tough conversations surround assessment, NWEA looks inward to define their role in the space and work together with educators, administrators, students, and families to improve the culture around testing and data. It’s a challenging, introspective moment for the industry, but Minnich and NWEA welcome the challenge.</p>
<p>“It’s up to organizations like ours to lead the way and encourage those conversations around what success looks like for students in the classroom, for teachers, building leaders, and district leaders,” Minnich says. “Last on that list is what success looks like for those of us in the assessment industry. At NWEA, we’re committed to improving outcomes for students and schools first, not our own bottom line.”</p>
<p>After more than four decades, thousands of partnerships, and millions of students served, where does NWEA go from here? Minnich and the team at NWEA continue to lay the groundwork for a very different organization for the next generation of teachers and students.</p>
<p>“I hope it’s not long before we are partnered with schools much deeper than we are right now,” he says. “That our assessments aren’t just a three-times-a-year event but, instead, that we’re woven into the fabric of what educators do, from goal setting and school improvement to identifying gaps and targeting interventions. Not just for a handful of schools and districts, but for all of them. That’s how we truly make our mission a reality.”</p>
<p>The mission continues, and this pursuit doesn’t end with a test. Because when assessment is done right, when it’s purposeful, beneficial, and meaningful, when it’s one part of a well-designed system of solutions, it’s not the end of anything. It’s only the beginning.</p>
<p style="font-size: 11px;">*Next Generation Science Standards is a registered trademark of Achieve. Neither Achieve nor the lead states and partners that developed the Next Generation Science Standards were involved in the production of this product, and do not endorse it.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resource-center/resource/on-a-mission-to-help-all-kids-learn/">On a mission to help all kids learn</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MAP Growth checks the boxes that matter most</title>
		<link>/resource-center/resource/map-growth-checks-the-boxes-that-matter-most/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 03:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resource-center/resource/map-growth-checks-the-boxes-that-matter-most/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resource-center/resource/map-growth-checks-the-boxes-that-matter-most/">MAP Growth checks the boxes that matter most</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resource-center/resource/map-growth-checks-the-boxes-that-matter-most/">MAP Growth checks the boxes that matter most</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reliability and accuracy: How MAP Growth measures up</title>
		<link>/resource-center/resource/reliability-and-accuracy-how-map-growth-measures-up/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 03:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resource-center/resource/reliability-and-accuracy-how-map-growth-measures-up/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Good educational decisions rely on good measurement. Whether you’re making decisions that guide the learning path of a single student or decisions that drive change on the system- or program-wide</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resource-center/resource/reliability-and-accuracy-how-map-growth-measures-up/">Reliability and accuracy: How MAP Growth measures up</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Good educational decisions rely on good measurement. Whether you’re making decisions that guide the learning path of a single student or decisions that drive change on the system- or program-wide level, you’ll need accurate information from the start.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nwea.org/map-growth/">MAP® Growth<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></a> provides the most precise and powerful assessment data available. Easy-to-use reports transform raw growth and performance figures into actionable insights, so teachers can personalize instruction and administrators can drive improvement on a larger scale.</p>
<h3>The gold standard of reliability and accuracy</h3>
<p>Innovation is in our DNA. As a research-based, not-for-profit assessment organization, our singular mission is to help all students learn. We continually perfect adaptive tests and hone norms to make data relevant, robust, and valuable for kids and their teachers.</p>
<p>MAP Growth is trusted by educators in over 146 countries as a source of high-quality data to track learning and growth. Here are just a few of the elements that set MAP Growth apart:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>A deep test item bank. </strong>With 50,000 unique items developed and vetted by our researchers, MAP Growth lets students accurately show what they know and are ready to learn next in numerous subjects, including math and reading—in both English and <a href="https://www.nwea.org/map-growth/map-spanish/">Spanish</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Just the right number of items.</strong> By asking students the right number of questions—not too many or too few—we minimize the standard error of measurement and protect instructional time.</li>
<li><strong>A mature and stable scale.</strong> Our RIT scale measures student performance consistently across time, independent of if kids are below, on, or above grade level, to provide a clear view of what’s working for students and what needs improvement.</li>
<li><strong>National norms</strong>. Our norms, based on anonymous assessment data from over 10.2 million students, give educators the ability to accurately evaluate students based on a representative sample of the US school-age population, not simply based on others who have taken the test. Tracking across the state and nation provides a clear view of how students compare.</li>
<li><strong>Alignment with Common Core and other state standards.</strong> MAP Growth test items align to standards in all 50 states, whether you follow Common Core or have your own standards.</li>
<li><strong>Accessibility features.</strong> Braille, screen readers, and other items provide assurance that every child’s knowledge is being measured accurately.</li>
<li><strong>College readiness predictions.</strong> MAP Growth also provides the most accurate predictions for college readiness tests for grades 5–9 (SAT®) and 10 (ACT®).</li>
</ul>
<h3>Great data is the backbone of success</h3>
<p>Pinpointing achievement and growth in students, classrooms, schools, and districts is impossible without precise information. Solid, reliable data takes the guesswork out of decision-making. When data is used to nurture struggling students or challenge high performers, it becomes the backbone of their future success. The combination of a student-centered focus and top-tier data makes MAP Growth the best choice for achieving your goals, from addressing the goals of struggling students to informing instruction and more.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resource-center/resource/reliability-and-accuracy-how-map-growth-measures-up/">Reliability and accuracy: How MAP Growth measures up</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 features your assessment tool must have</title>
		<link>/resource-center/resource/3-features-your-assessment-tool-must-have/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 02:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resource-center/resource/3-features-your-assessment-tool-must-have/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resource-center/resource/3-features-your-assessment-tool-must-have/">3 features your assessment tool must have</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resource-center/resource/3-features-your-assessment-tool-must-have/">3 features your assessment tool must have</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 ways to promote reading fluency after grade 3</title>
		<link>/resource-center/resource/3-ways-to-promote-reading-fluency-after-grade-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 16:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resource-center/resource/3-ways-to-promote-reading-fluency-after-grade-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Oral reading fluency is one of the essential components of early literacy. Like its counterparts—phonics, phonemic awareness, vocabulary, and reading comprehension—fluency is often prioritized in the K–3 classroom. Fluency is central in early</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resource-center/resource/3-ways-to-promote-reading-fluency-after-grade-3/">3 ways to promote reading fluency after grade 3</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oral reading fluency is one of the essential components of early literacy. Like its counterparts—<a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ovae/pi/AdultEd/essential-components-reading.pdf">phonics, phonemic awareness, vocabulary, and reading comprehension</a>—fluency is often prioritized in the K–3 classroom.</p>
<p>Fluency is central in early learning classrooms because early learners see the most rapid growth and change in their reading rate and accuracy as their skills improve. This rapid growth is largely due in part to frequent practice in the classroom, with teachers taking every opportunity to encourage their younger students to read out loud. This focus on the reading experience in primary classrooms is only intensifying as read-by-grade-3 initiatives influence teachers nationwide to prioritize fluency early and often, to prepare students ahead of that pivotal decision-point year.</p>
<h3>What reading instruction looks like in fourth grade and beyond</h3>
<p>After third grade, explicit fluency instruction often takes a backseat to other literacy competencies, though not for lack of things to cover. Students reading fluently by third grade still need to learn how to break down multisyllabic words, improve their word-attack skills, and receive instruction in morpheme analysis and prosody. Students with good automaticity with simpler text move to more complex text, while maintaining their rate, word-attack skills, and reading with expression. For students with unfinished learning in foundational skills the need is more dire, as a lack of fluency instruction can cause them to fall further behind.</p>
<p>Time is a major factor in this decision. Oral reading fluency is not always explicitly listed in the standards beyond third grade and, when it is, it may not be prioritized, as it’s not measured on the state summative test. Additionally, teachers working with students beyond third grade may be less familiar with the pedagogy for approaching these next-level fluency skills, simply because it’s not part of their standard practice. Also, existing fluency assessments may not be developed with fourth- and fifth-graders in mind and often lack age-appropriate reading content or interfaces.</p>
<p>The consequences for limiting explicit fluency and foundational skills instruction and assessment to early learners are especially impactful to struggling readers. If reading is difficult and frustrating, students are less likely to read. These same students will limit their exposure to complex vocabulary and syntax. Without practice in the classroom, they may stop reading aloud altogether, as most readers are not doing much reading aloud after the primary grades. Their peers who are stronger readers will continue to improve, widening the gap in the classroom and beyond. In fact, reading ability in third grade <a href="http://blogs.edweek.org/edweek/inside-school-research/2011/04/the_disquieting_side_effect_of.html">is a strong predictor of on-time high school graduation rate</a>.</p>
<h3>How to build fluency in older readers</h3>
<p>There are many opportunities for teachers and coaches to strengthen oral reading fluency beyond third grade for students reading on, above, or below grade level. Some of the strategies below can even be incorporated into other subjects, in social studies or science, for example, for a multidisciplinary approach that saves teacher time and gives students more opportunities to practice.</p>
<div>
<ol>
<li><strong><em>Scaffolding</em></strong>Scaffolding is the method of breaking down learning into smaller, right-sized blocks or ideas to better support students as they learn. Scaffolding strategies for oral reading fluency can take a lot of different approaches including:
<ul style="margin-bottom: 10px;">
<li>Students reading aloud to one another to create a feedback loop</li>
<li>A teacher pre-reading a text with students to introduce complex vocabulary before the students encounter the text on their own</li>
<li>Setting up recording stations for students to record themselves reading aloud and play recordings back to hear themselves and make improvements</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong><em> Creative read-aloud opportunities</em></strong>In addition to individual students reading aloud to the whole class from a textbook or fiction book, teachers can encourage fluency practice with reader theater. Students perform stories, poetry, or short plays aloud with small groups, with their lines at-the-ready. This is a fun way for students to practice their inflection, clarity, and speed with engaging material.</li>
<li><strong><em> Assessment</em></strong><a href="https://www.nwea.org/map-reading-fluency/">MAP® Reading Fluency<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></a> from NWEA is expanding coverage to better support at-risk fourth- and fifth-grade students. Additional passage levels, expanding to 1000L, support this wider range of early readers. Teachers can use the computer-adaptive, benchmark test to measure students’ oral reading fluency, literal comprehension, and foundational skills. Speech-recognition technology records and automatically scores students for immediate, objective scoring for an entire class in about 20 minutes.
<p>Available in English and Spanish, MAP Reading Fluency can be used as a benchmark or progress monitoring tool. It can be especially helpful to pinpoint the needs and gaps of struggling readers to help them work on specific skills in small groups or with additional interventions.</li>
</ol>
</div>
<h3>Going forward</h3>
<p>The need for fluency instruction does not disappear at the conclusion of third grade. To ensure they’re providing students with comprehensive literacy instruction, teachers and administrators should work together to find opportunities to continue fluency education and practice in the classroom, particularly for students at risk of falling behind. It’s a sound investment in future academic success.</p>
<style><!-- /* Fixes a nested list and starts its own counter */ body.resource-center .asset_holder.html_layout .txtcol ol ul li, body.resource-center .asset_holder.html_layout .txtcol ol ul ol{ counter-increment: sub-item; margin-left: 20px; list-style: disc; } body.resource-center .asset_holder.html_layout .txtcol ol ul li:first-child, body.resource-center .asset_holder.html_layout .txtcol ol ul ol:first-child{ counter-reset: sub-item; } body.resource-center .asset_holder.html_layout .txtcol ol ul li::before{ content: ''; } body.resource-center .asset_holder.html_layout .txtcol ol ol li::before{ content: counter(sub-item)". "; } --></style>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resource-center/resource/3-ways-to-promote-reading-fluency-after-grade-3/">3 ways to promote reading fluency after grade 3</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reach More Students</title>
		<link>/resource-center/resource/reach-more-students-equity-social-video/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jake.weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 05:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prd.cms.nwea.io/resource-center/resource/reach-more-students-equity-social-video/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resource-center/resource/reach-more-students-equity-social-video/">Reach More Students</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/resource-center/resource/reach-more-students-equity-social-video/">Reach More Students</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">NWEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
